<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ismaël Lachheb</title>
    <description>Welcome to my Development Blog, Here, you will find blog post about Data Science, software development, my projects or FOSS related article.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <author>
      <name>Ismaël Lachheb </name>
      <email>ismael.lachheb@protonmail.com</email>
      <uri></uri>
    </author>
    
      <item>
        <title>Development Journal : GabTag 1</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here, I would like to present my experience making my first Linux Gtk application. I will mostly talk about the issues i encountered because it is the most interesseting part and the most informative too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;issues-encontered&quot;&gt;Issues encontered&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;first-issue-setting-up-travis-ci&quot;&gt;First issue : Setting up Travis-ci&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the hardest thing for me has been to set up Travis-ci, I first set up a Travis-org CI (a deprecated version of Travis) instead of the classic Travis-ci and I was not able to transfer my project in the right version of travis. I had to create a new GitHub repository to fix that. Then when it was done, I had to guess that Travis need the python3-gi package and the PygObjext pip package to be able to test the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;second-issue-make-the-grid-box-scrollable&quot;&gt;Second issue : make the grid box scrollable&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second i encountered was the layout, to make my grid layout scrollable, i had to put it inside a GtkAspectFrame and a GtkViewport which are not the easiest objects to access with glade. Anyway my layout is still not completely satisfying because i always need to resize the size of my panel when i’m using Gabtag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;third-issue--using-gdkpixbufprolog&quot;&gt;Third issue : Using GdkPixbufProlog&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally the third issue which is still not fixed is with gdkpixbuf class. It is a bit surprising how showing an image can be hard in gtk. I had to use an external API called Pillow to show a byte image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even more surprising, for some image, the gtk pixbuf is not showing a scaled version of it but a deformed version of it. This issue is only apparing on my application so I hope I will be able to quickly fix it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion-&quot;&gt;Conclusion :&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you get a solution for those issues, you can send my an email to ismael.lachheb@protonmail.com. Otherwise, i hope my experience can help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//GabTag-Journal-Development-1</link>
        <link href="http://localhost:4000/GabTag-Journal-Development-1"/>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/GabTag-Journal-Development-1</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
